All right, real quick, the five stages of creative, I made this,
this little chart. So if you've never worked in production, or maybe you have,
but this is a, this is,
this is centered on performance ads. This, this chart right here. Okay?
So, and these are the different roles you have on the left. You have the role,
the stage, the sections and the steps.
You have the creative strategist who's responsible for the research and copy.
You're getting the product, customer research and defining the ad angles.
And then once that's done,
you move over to the content creation side where scripting is involved. Um,
casting and scheduling as well as production, right?
And this is where whether you are outsourcing your, your, your work,
or you're shooting it in house, or you're doing it yourself, um,
this is where that's done.
So you always start with the research and then the scripting,
and then the shooting. Then once you're done, then it's, uh,
then it's media management.
And this is where you're uploading and organizing all of your footage and, uh,
getting it prepared to deploy to your editors. Uh,
and typically, you know, if you're an editor,
you're getting like these creative briefs of, of the project. Um, here are what,
you know, here are the objectives, here are the requirements, blah, blah, blah.
Sometimes you don't get this at all and it's,
they just jump a bunch of stuff on you. And that's, you know,
that's part of the, part of the job. But, um,
what's really important to focus on is the editing stage where you have the
editing, the video review, the final cut, the variations. As you know,
as an editor, you go through a lot of iterations and approvals,
especially if you're working with a bigger team or other people involved.
They're gonna review your stuff and they're gonna make comments and they're
gonna ask you to change things even if you don't agree with it. But that's life.
Um, because afterwards, when they do deploy it, um,
there is a process that I'll share, uh, when it comes to media buying,
how to test your ads the right way. So when I know I,
I shared that little circular chart with you,
but once you do find winning variations from your edits, um,
the creative strategist or the media buyer should report what those are to the
editor. At least have a meeting with them to go over what worked, what didn't,
and if, uh, if it didn't, excuse me, sorry.
It's this feedback feedback loop that you need to be working with your creative
strategist or your media buyers as an editor because you're not the one in there
running the ads most of the time. And you need to be learning from the data.
And so if, if, if they're not providing you that, that information,
then you need to go out and seek it because it's very easy to just be like,
okay, well what's the next thing? Um, you know,
I've noticed that this is probably the most challenging thing in, in,
in teams is keeping that feedback loop aligned.
Because what the media buyer's seeing versus what the editor is seeing is,
is are two different things and getting everybody up to speed is incredibly,
incredibly important, especially when you're doing performance ads. Alright,
so that wraps up this section, part three.
Thank you so much for watching and I hope you guys got some value.
I will see you guys in the next one. Cheers.